CHETHAN MYSURU RADHAKRISHNA

Pursuing Master's in Data and Knowledge Engineering

@ chethanmr.2694@gmail.com

J +49 17636817295

Arnold-Zweig Strasse 4, 39120, Magdeburg, Germany chethanmysore.github.io/portfolio

Magdeburg, Germany

in chethan-radhakrishna-94310010b/

chethanMysore



ABOUT ME!

I am a data science enthusiast with an inclination towards visual exploration of trends in data. I am also a skilled web developer with a collective experience of 4.5 years. However, I believe in the idea that "What we know is a drop and what we don't know is an ocean".

PROJECTS

Small Vessel Segmentation using Deformation-aware Semi-supervised learning

Otto-von-Guericke University

April 2021 - Ongoing

Application of DS6 Deformation-aware Semi-supervised learning published by Soumick Chatterjee et.al., to 7T MRA images and improvement of segmentation quality by Max Intensity Projection (MIP) comparisons.

Technologies Used: Python, PyTorch, nibabel, scikit-image, cuda

Interpretable Machine Learning to Understand Participant Evolution in Longitudinal Cohort Study Data **Otto-von-Guericke University**

Cctober 2019 - March 2020

The project aims at identifying evolutionary trends in longitudinal cohort data of a German population in Pomerania. The study focuses on explainable AI to explore the results of a machine learning model to derive critical factors influencing the diagnosis of Hepatic Steatosis. Worked on pre-processing, R-API development and visualization of model results using react-redux dashboard.

Technologies Used: R, react.js, redux, saga, canvas.js(for interactive graph visualizations)

Information Retrieval System

Otto-von-Guericke University

October 2019 - January 2020

This is a console java application which indexes files and directories and allows users to execute boolean queries on them. Here we used Apache Lucene to tokenize, index and guery text in a directory(nested) or files. The application aims at achieving disambiguation of search terms and ranking of results based on relevance score. Technologies Used: Apache Lucene, java, maven

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Data and Knowledge Engineering

Otto-von-Guericke University, Magdeburg

2019 - 2022 (Ongoing)

Coursework:

- Machine Learning
- Data Mining
- Advanced Topics in Data Mining(Stream Mining)
- Visual Analytics
- Knowledge Engineering and Digital Humanities
- Deep Learning
- Swarm Intelligence
- Information Retrieval
- Distributed Data Management
- Data Management for Engineering Appli-

B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering

Vidyavardhaka College of Engineering, India

2012 - 2016

SKILLS

Programming: Pvthon SQL Splunk mongoDB Node.js React.js C# C++

Java



Gesture Recognition For Interactive Systems Using Kinect V2

Vidhyavardhaka College of Engineering

iii November 2015 - April 2016

Developed a WPF application to recognize user gestures using Microsoft Kinect V2 sensor. The application binds different mouse and keyboard inputs to gestures performed by users and thereby allowing them to interact with the system. Authentication of users is performed with face recognition algorithm developed using PCA(Principal Component Analysis) to compare grey scale images of faces.

Technologies Used: .NET framework 4.5, WPF, Kinect V2 SDK, C#

Libraries: Scikit-Learn Keras Tensorflow PyTorch **NLTK** spaCy gensim **IDEs:** Visual Studio **Eclipse** Jupyter Google Colab **Version Control and CICD:** Git Lab Octopus **Jenkins** Docker

EXPERIENCE

Big Data Analyst Intern

Bosch Engineering Gmbh

April 2021 - September 2021

Abstatt

Worked as an intern on big-data analysis in project management metrics. Created complex data preparation and wrangling queries and interactive dashboard visualizations in Splunk Enterprise tool. These visualizations are used every day by various levels of management to track and analyse the progress of several ongoing projects at Bosch Engineering both in Germany and in the US. Also, worked on automatic dashboard deployment scripts in python.

Technologies: Splunk, Python, XML

Software Developer - Work Student Metratec Gmbh

■ June 2019-Feb 2021 Magdeburg

Worked as a full stack web developer. Handled API integration with react-redux dashboards. worked on real time data using web sockets. worked on event sourcing and re-Solve(a CQRS framework built using node.js). Managed Gitlab pipeline and docker configurations with yaml.

Technologies: Reactjs, nodejs, reSolve, web sockets, node-red

Software Engineer

Happiest Minds Technologies Pvt Ltd

October 2016 - January 2019

Bengaluru, India

Contributed as a full stack web developer. Worked on ASP.NET MVC applications and Web API services. Worked on react.js and redux to implement stateful front-end designs. Worked exclusively on Health Care domain with the knowledge of online data exchange standards such as HL7. Worked on AWS EC2, S3 buckets, Simple Mail Service and Lambda(for deploying micro services). Interacted with clients to understand requirements and effectively communicated the innovative ideas to solve their problems.

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC/WebAPI, C, Reactjs, nodejs, AWS

LANGUAGES

English				
Kannada		•	•	•
Hindi		•	•	
German				

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Article

• Chethan M R Adarsh M V Akarsh M S Karunesh Gurkar, Prashanth Kumar (Guide) (2016). "Gesture Recognition for Interactive Systems Using Kinect v2". In: *International Journal of Innovative Research in Computer and Communication Engineering (IJIRCCE)*, 4(5):9186–9191, 05 2016. ISSN: 2320-9801. DOI: 10.15680/IJIRCCE.2015.0405108. URL: http://www.ijircce.com/upload/2016/may/108_22_Gesture_2%20HARD.pdf.

ACHIEVEMENTS



'Individual Excellence Award' for outstanding contribution to the project and customer happiness.



'Mindful Egg Head Award' for demonstrating good composure and interpersonal skills.